rawsugar.com 2007-06-19

# RawSugar - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy 

RawSugar is firmly committed to protecting the privacy of our users. Your privacy is important to us. We want to provide a safe, secure experience for all of our users. Because we gather certain types of information about users of our site, we feel you should be aware of the terms surrounding the capture and use of that information. Strong electronic privacy is an essential ingredient in the success of the Internet as an online medium. The following discloses what information we gather, how we use or disseminate it, and how you can change it. 

## Information Collection and Use 

RawSugar is the sole owner of all information collected on this site. Some of this information we recognize is personal to our users and further, each user retains a non-exclusive, irrevocable right to reuse any comments, tags or other information saved on this site. We will not sell, trade, share, or rent personal information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. We collect personal information from our users at several different points on our web site. We collect statistical information such as page views on an aggregated basis. Such information allows us to find out what areas users visit most frequently and what services users access the most. It also allows us to create a better overall experience for our users. We may share this information with advertisers and potential and actual partners, but only in the aggregate. We do not consider this statistical and aggregated information to be personal. We collect tags, notes and URLs that users save in our database. We do not consider this information to be personal. We collect user names, email addresses, mailing list preferences. We consider this information to be personal. 

## Registration 

In order to use RawSugar, a user must first complete a registration form. During registration a user is asked to give their contact information. RawSugar collects information our users submit to us such as their name and e-mail address to allow us to identify users and notify them of changes or updates to our service. We also collect personal information submitted by our users in filling out their personal profile which may include company name, address, phone number and other items. RawSugar uses a person's email address and name only when a user invites a friend via email to join or explore the site, when a user requests to add another user to the site, and when RawSugar sends notifications to a user related to their use of the service. This information is used to enhance the users experience on RawSugar and is never sold, rented, traded or shared. 

## Cookies 

To enhance your experience at RawSugar, we use a feature on your Internet browser called a "cookie". Cookies are small bits of data that are written to your hard drive when you visit a web site. A cookie file can contain information such as a user or session ID to track the pages you've visited or a user name and password so you don't have to re-enter it throughout your visit. A cookie can't read data off of your hard drive or read other cookies created by other web sites. We use cookies for such things as remembering user names, passwords and preferences. We may also use cookies at our site to better understand how users visit our site so that we know what areas and features are the most popular. Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver quicker service and a more personalized site experience for our users. You are always free to reject cookies by turning them off in your browser. However, doing this will hinder performance and negatively impact your experience at our site. 

## Log Files 

We may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not currently linked to personally identifiable information. 

## Links 

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that RawSugar is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

## Newsletter 

RawSugar may, from time to time, use e-mail addresses in order to send out electronic newsletters, service update notices and other information to our users. Users may select not to receive marketing communications from us but this setting does not apply to contact regarding usage and technical issues that may arise. 

## Invite A Friend 

If a user elects to invite a friend to use our service, we may ask them for the friend's name and email address. We will automatically send the friend an email inviting them to explore the site. We store this email address for the purpose of automatically adding the respondent to the friends list of the user sending the invitation, and also to send reminders of the invitation. We do not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations and invitation reminders. The friend may contact RawSugar to request the removal of this information from our database. 

## Special Offers 

We may send new members a welcoming email, which may also be used to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our "How You Can Change the Information" below. 

## Opting out of e-mail updates and newsletters 

RawSugar gives its users an option to "Opt Out" of receiving information such as e-mail updates or newsletters via their user accounts. RawSugar may still send you a "Welcome" email. However, after that, RawSugar will not send you further information but this setting does not apply to contact regarding usage and technical issues that may arise. 

## Changing your personal information 

RawSugar allows you to change or correct your personal information at any time. To do so, simply log into your account, go to your account profile and edit the information previously submitted. 

## Security 

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We will do our best to safeguard your personal information but no guarantee or warranty is made or inferred in this regard. 

## Changes in Our Privacy Policy 

If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our web site so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will attempt to notify users via email but users who choose not to supply any email address or a valid, current email address will not receive such notifications and should check the posted Privacy Policy. 

## Contact Us 

Please let us know if you have any questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy or the web site, please contact us. Current contact information can be reached through a link displayed at the bottom of all web pages on this site.

For more information about RawSugar, please contact us via email, at [info@rawsugar.com](mailto:info@rawsugar.com).
